Marcel Breuer
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1923-1986, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-6, OV 47; Reels 5708-5717; 5.3 linear feet)
  Jones, Douglas (University of Bristol, U.K.), 1967 (1 letter)
  Jones, Noel W. (district engineer, OCS), 1968 (1 letter)
  Jones, Paul K. (mayor of Shaker Heights, Ohio), 1970 (1 letter)
  Jones, Theodore S. (Institute of Contemporary Art), 1950-1951 (2 letters)
  Joraschek, Josef (architect), 1965 (1 letter)
  Jordi, Beat, 1970-1976 (13 letters): 12 from Breuer
  Jordy, William H. (Yale University), 1951 (2 letters)
  Jossa, Mario, 1966-1976 (37 letters): 28 from Breuer
  Joyce, Nora, 1934 (1 letter)
  Junyer, Joan [?]1961 (1 letter)
  Kacmarcik, Frank, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Kaffka, Péter (C. E. Pratt & Péter Kaffka, Architects), 1950 (1 letter)
  Kahlen, Wolfgang, 1965 (1 letter)
  Kahn, Hugo, 1968 (1 letter)
  Kahn, Louis I. (Oscar Stonorov and Louis I. Kahn Associated Architects), 1945-1966 (5 letters): see American Society of Planners and Architects (ASPA)
  Kalmai, K., 1924 (1 letter)
  Kálmán, Timon, 1967 (2 letters)
  Kalnay, Ferenc, 1938 (1 letter)
  Kamer, Henri A. (Kamer, Inc.), 1964-1966 (2 letters)
  Kamphoefner, Henry L. (School of Design, North Carolina State College), 1951-1954 (6 letters)
  Kandinsky, Lina, 1969-1976 (mentioned in 2 letters from Constance Breuer)
  Kane, Ervin (Viewtone Television), 1946 (2 letters)
  Kaneko, Masanori (Kagawa Prefectural Government, Japan), 1970 (1 letter)
  Kann, Henry Robert, 1951 (1 letter)
  Karajabey, Ayla, 1966 (telegram from Breuer)
  Karlock, Michael (Benton & Bowles), 1946 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Karsten, Thomas and Marilyn (American Trading Company), 1963-1975 (8 letters)
  Kaspar, Karl (Verlag Gerd Hatje GMBH), 1955 (2 letters)
  Kass, Gertrud [?], 1939 (1 letter)
  Katsuyama, S., undated (1 letter)
  Kaufman, Stanley Lloyd, 1950 (1 letter): see Project File for UNESCO
  Kaufmann, Edgar J. (Kaufmann Department Store), 1954-1963 (2 letters)
  Kazi, Abdul-Rassak, 1966 (2 letters)
  Kazin, Alfred, 1971 (1 letter)
  W. R. Keating & Company, 1962 (1 letter): concerns shipment of Alexander Calder sculpture
  Keller, Dieter, 1965 (2 letters)
  Kelly, John Terence (architect), 1964 (1 letter)
  Kelly, Virginia Whitmore, 1949 (1 letter)
  Kennedy, Edith (Robert Woods Kennedy's mother), 1939 (1 letter)
  Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1961-1963 (3 letters): from the White House
  Kennedy, Robert Woods (first architect in Gropius-Breuer office, Cambridge, Massachusetts), undated and 1950 (3 letters): see American Society of Planners and Architects (ASPA)
  Kennerly, Albert (Kennerly Construction Company, Inc.), 1947 (1 letter)
  Keogh, Eugene J. (Halpin, Keogh & St. John), 1970 (1 letter)
  Kepes, György (architect) and Juliet, undated and 1924-1978 (29 letters)
  Kertész, André, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Kertész, Gyula, 1938 (1 letter)
  Kessler-Gallacher & Burton, Seagram-Distillers Corporation, 1954-1963 (5 letters)
  Ketchum, Morris (Ketchum, Gina & Sharp, Architects), 1957-1963 (25 letters)
  Ketchum, Phillips (Ketchum Building Corporation), 1967 (4 letters)
  Keyser, William, 1964 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Kida, Miho, 1975 (2 letters)
  Kiley, Dan, 1955 (1 letter)
  Kilham, Walter H. (R. B. O'Connor and W. H. Kilham, Architects), 1951-1960 (2 letters)
  Kimura, Akira, 1965 (1 letter): includes photograph of family E. & F. King & Company, 1946 (2 letters)
  King, Helen (William Morrow & Company, Inc., Publishers), 1951 (1 letter)
  Kipnis, Leonid (Leonid Kipnis Gallery), 1954 (1 letter)
  Kirkconnell, Watson, 1967 (1 invitation): to George Washington Awards Dinner in honor of Breuer, Kirkconnell, and Hans Selye
  Kistler, Daniel, undated and 1964 (2 letters)
  Kivett & Myers & McCallum (Architects - Engineers), undated (1 letter)
  Kleyer, Bertel and Erwin Kleyer, 1946-1954 (10 letters)
  Klöckner (Deimel, Klöckner, Koebel), 1959 (1 letter)
  Kniffin, Ogden ("Nif"; inventor of Colorforms) and Kitty, 1950-1960 (5 letters): 3 from Breuer
  Knoll, Hans G. and Florence (H. G. Knoll Associates, Inc.), undated and 1945-1961 (12 letters); see Project File for UNESCO
  Knoll International, Inc., 1971-1977 (7 letters): see Vidal, Yves
  Knox, Sanka (New York Times), 1960 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Kobler, John (Saturday Evening Post), 1959 (1 letter)
  Koch, Alexander, 1948-1961 (2 letters)
  Koerfer, Jacques and Christina, undated and 1964-1977 (18 letters)
  Kolozsváry-Kiss, árpád, 1957 (2 letters)
  Kondor, E. ("Pista"), 1937 (1 letter)
  König, Dr. Heinrich, 1954-1959 (3 letters)
  Konwiser, Inc., 1954 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Kootz, Samuel B. (Kootz Art Gallery), 1954-1956 (2 letters)
  Koran, Spencer, 1974-1975 (4 letters): from Breuer's office
  Korn, Arthur (Architectural Association School of Architecture), 1947-1956 (2 letters)
  Kornfeld, Albert, 1956 (1 letter)
  Kortan, Enis (Turkish architect), 1956-1960 (3 letters)
  Koudela, E. Hugi (Deeter Ritchey Sippel), 1968 (1 letter)
  Koyama, Shin (photographer), 1974 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Kósa, Zoltán, 1962 (1 letter)
  Kozlowski, Jean Paul and Shirley, 1960-1972 (2 letters)
  Kraemer, Friedrich Wilhelm (architect), 1955 (1 letter)
  Kramer, Edwin R., 1950 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Krausz, László, 1957-1968 (2 letters)
  Krivátsky-Szüts, ádám (Hungarian architect), 1960 (1 letter)
  Kri anac, Dr. Matko, 1974 (1 letter)
  Ku, Danna Morison, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Kuenzle, Creed (Swiss architect), 1959 (1 letter)
  Kuh, Katharine (Art Institute of Chicago), undated and 1951 (2 letters)
  Kulkarni, Ashok, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Keith R. Kunhardt Associates, Inc., 1966 (1 letter)
  Kunst Kabinett Klihm, Munich, 1956 (1 letter)
  Kuwayama, A. (Kuwayama & Company, Inc.), 1945 (1 letter)
  Laaff, George, 1960 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Laboratoires Sarget, 1970 (1 letter)
  Lacey, Joseph (Eero Saarinen Associates), 1957 (2 letters)
  Ladd, Fred, 1965 (1 letter)
  LaFarge, Bancel: see American Institute of Architects
  La Joie Par Les Livres, 1964 (1 letter)
  Lalonde, Gisele and Jean-Louis, undated and 1955 (2 letters)
  Laminated Veneers, Inc., 1948 (2 letters)
  Lamson, Jarvis (Functional Furniture, Inc.), 1947-1948 (9 letters): see Noyes, Eliot
  Landram, Fred, 1947 (1 letter)
  M. Landsberg Stationery Company, 1960 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Landsberg, William W., 1953-1959 (5 letters)
  Lang, George E. (Restaurant & Waldorf Associates, Inc.), 1967-1968 (2 letters)
  Lányi, George, 1939-1946 (2 letters)
  L'Architecture d'Aujourd'hui, 1954 (3 letters)
  La Rinascente Compasso d'Oro, 1955-1965 (43 letters)
  Larson, Else M. (Mrs. Arthur W. Larson), 1963 (2 letters)
  Laseau, Paul, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  László, Carl, 1964 (1 letter)
  Lauck, Peter (Morton Sundour Company, Inc.), 1950 (1 letter)
  Lauper, Peter (Fraser's), 1955 (1 letter)
  Laurenti, André, 1959-1968 (8 letters)
  Lautman, Robert C. (photographer), 1973 (1 letter): from Herbert Beckhard
  La Verne Originals, 1947 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Lavigueur, Gilles (architect), 1967 (1 letter): includes 2 photographs of a chair
  Lawrence, John W. (Tulane University), 1953 (1 letter)
  Le Corbusier, 1957 (1 letter): from Walter Gropius to friends concerning Le Corbusier's 70th birthday; see also Project File for UNESCO
  Lee, Duk, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Lee, Richard C. (mayor of New Haven), 1964 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Al Paul Lefton Company, Inc., Advertising, 1949-1950 (2 letters)
  Lehigh Furniture Corporation, 1951 (1 letter)
  Leibowitz, Matthew, 1946 (1 letter)
  Leight, Lillian, 1972 (1 letter)
  Leighton, O. S., 1946-1951 (11 letters)
  Lemm, H. J., undated (1 letter)
  Lennon, Jacques E., 1975 (1 letter)
  Leontieff, Wassily, 1947 (1 letter)
  Lercaro, His Eminence Jacques Cardinal, 1969-1970 (2 letters)
  Lescaze, William (architect), 1954 (1 letter)
  Lever, Lance, 1966 (1 letter)
  Levin, Arnold B., 1954 (1 letter)
  Levine, Leon, 1971 (1 letter)
  Lévy, Vilmos (Hungarian sculptor), undated and 1938 (2 letters)
  Lewin, Kurt and G., 1944-1947 (4 letters)
  Lewis, George Sherman (architect), 1946-1954 (4 letters): see Project File for UNESCO
  Li, Ying, 1947 (1 letter)
  Liberman, Tatiana and Alexander, 1969 (1 invitation): for cocktails with Helen Frankenthaler Librairie d'Art Ancien et Moderne, 1962-1963 (2 letters)
  Librairie Ernest Flammarion, 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Lili, S. Braun, 1936-1939 (8 letters)
  Lilinthal, Benjamin, 1956 (1 letter)
  Limbach, Scott (Limbach Company), 1976 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Lincoln Warehouse Corporation, 1951 (1 letter)
  Lindsay, John V. (mayor of New York) and Mary, 1967-1969 (5 letters)
  L'Industria Italiana del Cemento, 1975 (2 letters)
  Linke, Siegfried, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Lionni, Leonardo and Nora, 1962 (1 letter): see also International Design Conference, Aspen
  Littke, George, 1950 (1 letter)
  Liverant, Mrs. M. J., 1960 (1 letter)
  Lloyd, Eleanor B. (Mrs. H. Gates Lloyd), 1959 (1 letter)
  Lloyd, Miss M. E., 1939 (1 letter)
  Lobell, Mimi, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  L'Oeil, 1974-1975 (2 letters): from Breuer
  Lohse, Richard P. (editor, Bauen + Wohnen), 1950 (1 letter)
  Lombard, M. A. (M. A. Lombard & Son, Company, General Contractors), 1966 (1 letter)
  Long Beach Art Association, Inc., 1954 (1 letter)
  Longmans, Green & Company, Ltd., 1958 (1 letter)
  Lortz, R., 1946 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Louisiana State University, Department of Architecture, 1964 (1 letter)
  Lubroth, I. (Lubroth y Henriquez, Estudio de Arquitectura), 1975 (1 letter)
  Ludolf, H. G., 1933-1934 (2 letters)
  Lundy, Victor A., 1950-1951 (3 letters)
  Lunning, Just, 1956 (1 letter)
  Lurie, H. Lee, 1946-1947 (4 letters): see Project File for UNESCO
  Lutz, Pierre, 1961-1968 (2 letters): from Breuer Lydakis, George (Precision Metal Model Corporation), 1950-1955 (2 letters)
  Lydon, Ken, 1972 (1 letter)
  Lyles, Bissett, Carlisle & Wolff, 1955 (2 letters)
  Lyman, Bill, 1946 (3 letters)
  Lyn, Robert J., 1951 (2 letters)
  Lyndon, Maynard (architect), 1965 (1 letter)
  Maas, Carl ("Happy"/"Hap"; editor, House Beautiful), 1937-1946 (6 letters)
  Maas, Walter, 1947 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Macomber, George A. (Cambridge Trust Company), 1947 (2 letters)
  Madison, Bob, 1951 (1 letter)
  I. Magnin, San Francisco, 1961 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Magyar Album, 1956 (1 letter)
  Magyar épitomuvészek Szövetsége magazine, 1956-1977 (4 letters)
  Maki, Fumihiko (Harvard University), 1963 (1 letter) George E. Mallison Importing Company, 1950-1955 (2 letters)
  Manders, Dave, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Mandl, Zoltán, 1939 (1 letter)
  Manfred, Ernest F., 1966 (1 letter)
  Mang, Karl (architect), 1967 (1 letter)
  Manitoba, University of, Students' Architectural Society, 1953 (1 letter)
  Mantel, H. J., 1951 (1 letter)
  Manton, Mr. and Mrs. John, 1967 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Marbleloid, Inc., 1946 (1 letter)
  Marine-Air-Research Corporation, 1946 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Maroy, Jean-Paul, 1981 (1 letter): from Robert F. Gatje William L. Marshall, Ltd., 1944-1947 (8 letters)
  Marson, Bernard A. (architect), 1968 (1 letter)
  Marston, Natalie (Institute of Contemporary Art), 1951 (1 letter)
  Martens, Michel (Hedendaagse Kerkelijke Kunst), 1956-1957 (2 letters)
  Martignetti, Antonio, 1956 (1 letter)
  Martin, J. L. (architect), 1938 (1 letter)
  Martin, Leslie and Sadie, undated and 1954 (3 letters)
  Mary College and the Annunciation Priory, 1963-1976 (6 letters)
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Art Committee, 1968 (1 letter)
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Office of the President, 1961-1965 (2 letters)
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology Press, 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Massachusetts Institute of Technology, School of Architecture and Planning, 1958-1960 (4 letters)
  Massachusetts, University of, Amherst, 1968 (1 letter)
  Massenot, J. P. (éditions Techniques), 1974 (1 letter): from Breuer's office Master, Dipak C. (Master Sathe and Kothari, Architects), 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Mathews, Joseph F., 1956 (1 letter)
  Maucher, Helmut, 1976 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Maurer, Laurie, undated (3 letters)
  Mauser Kommandit-Gesellschaft, 1966 (1 letter)
  Mayekawa, Kunio, 1963 (1 letter)
  McClean-Smith, Betty, 1940 (1 letter)
  McComb, Peter K. and Karen, 1954-1956 (4 letters)
  McGarry, Ann M., 1947 (1 letter)
  McGill University, Montreal, 1967 (1 letter)
  McGlynn Associates, Inc., 1956 (1 letter)
  McGrath, Raymond (Office of Public Works, Dublin, Ireland), 1937-1969 (9 letters)
  McGraw-Hill Publications, 1967 (1 letter)
  McGuinness, William J. (Pratt Institute), 1951 (1 letter)
  McIntyre, A. McVoy, 1950-1951 (2 letters)
  McLaughlin, Peter, 1959 (1 letter)
  McMillan, Louis and Peggy (Architects' Collaborative), 1945-1946 (2 letters)
  McVitty, John D., 1946 (1 letter)
  John O. Meadows Associates, Ltd., 1984-1985 (2 letters)
  Medical Economics, 1960 (1 letter)
  Meier, Richard Alan, undated and 1957-1967 (5 letters)
  Meldrum, Andrew, 1956 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Meller, Herbert, 1969-1970 (4 letters)
  Mellon, Mary, 1938 (1 letter)
  Meng, John J. (Hunter College), 1963 (1 letter)
  Menken, Julian (Julian Menken and Associates), 1964 (1 letter)
  Merit Studios, Inc., 1965 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Merle, André (André Merle Associates, Architectural Engineers), 1946 (1 letter)
  Merrill and Holmbren, Architects, 1954 (1 letter): concerns Campbell Building Company
  Merrill, Ruth P., 1950-1964 (2 letters)
  Metropolitan Milwaukee War Memorial, Inc., 1945 (4 letters): 1 to Walter Gropius
  Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1944-1975 (8 letters)
  Metropolitan Structures, Inc., 1974 (2 letters): from Breuer's office
  Metropolitan Washington Board of Trade, 1969 (2 letters)
  Meunier, John, 1957 (1 letter)
  México, Consulado Honorario de, 1938 (2 letters)
  Meyer-Bohe, Walter, 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Michaëlis, Lorenz S. (Swiss doctor), undated (1 letter)
  Michaelis-Lenolt, Ilse, 1937 (1 letter)
  Michaud, Marcel (Stylclair), 1950-1951 (3 letters)
  Michel, John (General American Transportation Corporation), 1947-1948 (2 letters)
  Michelson, Val (architect), 1970 (1 letter)
  Michigan, University of, Ann Arbor, 1957-1963 (19 letters)
  Middelhauve, Dr. F. G., 1963 (1 letter)
  Mies Van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1945 (1 letter): from Breuer introducing Sanford L. and Helen Berger, architects
  Mihályfy, Károlyné, 1966 (1 letter)
  Millar, L. R., 1935 (1 letter)
  Millard, Charles W., 1957 (1 letter)
  Miller Company, 1945-1947 (2 letters)
  Miller, Flora W. (Mrs. G. MacCulloch Miller), undated (1 letter)
  Miller, H. Wisner, 1968-1969 (2 letters)
  Herman Miller Furniture Company, 1951-1954 (4 letters): from Breuer
  Miller, Rev. John (St. Charles Seminary), 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Miller, Richard J., 1955 (1 letter)
  Miller, Steve, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Milliken, W. H. (Binney & Smith Company), 1951 (1 letter)
  Mills, Mrs. Edward E., 1954 (1 letter): from William W. Landsberg
  Mills, Willis N. (Sherwood, Mills and Smith, Architects), 1960-1969 (2 letters)
  Ministre d'état Chargé des Affaires Culturelles, 1963 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Minnesota Society of Architects, 1958 (1 letter)
  Minnesota, State of, Board of Registration, 1954 (2 letters)
  Minnesota, University of, 1953 (1 letter)
  Miró, Joan, 1959-1963 (2 letters): 1 from Breuer
  Mitchell and Ritchey, 1947 (2 letters)
  Mitchell, Mary, 1954 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Miya & Company, 1956 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Modern Industry, 1947 (1 letter)
  Modern Master Tapestries, Inc., 1974-1975 (4 letters): from Breuer's office
  Moffett, Toby, 1974 (1 letter)
  Moholy, Lucia, 1957-1958 (5 letters)
  Moholy-Nagy, László ("Lakci") and Sibyl, 1934-1955 (40 letters): includes a 1946 exhibition catalog for a Walter Gropius exhibition at the School of Design, Chicago; see also Hug, Hattula Moholy-Nagy
  Moldcast Products, Inc., 1950 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Molitor, Joseph W. (photographer), 1955-1975 (5 letters): 4 from Breuer
  Molnár, Farkas (Hungarian architect), undated and 1933-1940 (25 letters)
  Mongan, Agnes, 1938 (1 letter)
  Montague, Harvey, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Montgomery, Elizabeth (Mrs. Wilmot), 1950 (1 letter)
  Moore, Henry, 1946-1962 (13 letters): 6 from Breuer
  Moore, Joe A., 1945 (2 letters)
  Moore, Paul S. (architect), 1966-1967 (3 letters)
  Morassutti, Mangiarotti, 1961 (1 letter)
  Moretti, Bruno, 1936 (1 letter)
  Morgan, Alice, 1939 (1 letter)
  Morgan, Sherley W. (Princeton University), 1952 (3 letters)
  Móricz, Miklós, 1947 (1 letter)
  Morrell, Mrs. Ben, 1965 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Sydney Morrell & Company, Inc., 1973-1976 (4 letters)
  Morris, Walter (Fuller & Smith & Ross, Inc.), 1950 (1 letter)
  Morrow, Margot, 1950 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Mory, Bob, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Moschette, Angela, 1950 (1 letter)
  Motherwell, Robert, 1968 (1 letter)
  Muguruza Otaño, José María (architect), 1935-1967 (3 letters)
  Mulford, Edwin H., 1966 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Müller-Rehm, Klaus (architect), 1951 (1 letter)
  Mundipharma GmbH, Frankfurt, 1975-1976 (4 letters)
  Eduard Munz & Company, 1954-1959 (3 letters)
  Murray, J. A. (University of Toronto School of Architecture), 1947-1956 (3 letters)
  Murrow, Mrs. Edward R., 1961 (1 letter)
  Musée des Arts Décoratifs, 1969 (2 letters)
  Museu de Arte Moderna do Rio de Janeiro, 1954 (1 letter)
  Museu de Arte Moderna do São Paulo, 1956 (1 letter concerning IV Bienal de S. Paulo)
  Museum of Contemporary Crafts, 1967 (7 letters)
  Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1941-1976 (49 letters)
  Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago, 1967 (3 letters)
  Museum of the City of New York, 1959 (2 letters)
  Muskat, Irving E., 1968 (2 letters)
  Mutsu, Masako, 1964-1965 (2 letters): from Breuer
  Myers, John S. and Shirlee, 1955-1959 (4 letters)
  Myers, Ralph E., 1958 (2 letters)
  Myers, Robert L., 1950 (1 letter)
  Nadeau, Eleanor Saxe, 1950 (1 letter)
  Nader, Fouzieh, 1972 (2 letters)
  Nagare, Masayuki, 1963-1965 (6 letters): 5 letters from Breuer
  Nagel, Chester (architect), 1968 (1 letter)
  Nagy Iván, Dr. Vitéz (Ministry Secretary), undated (1 letter)
  Najibullah, Yousof, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Napier, Frieda (Mrs. Ian Napier), undated and 1937 (7 letters)
  Nathan, Carl H. (Suncraft), 1945 (1 letter)
  National Academy of Sciences/National Research Council, undated (1 letter)
  National Citizens for Johnson and Humphrey, 1964 (1 letter)
  National Committee of Arts, Letters and Sciences for John F. Kennedy for President, 1960 (2 letters)
  National Concrete Masonry Association, 1958-1959 (7 letters)
  National Council of American Soviet Friendship, Inc., Architects' Committee, 1944-1945 (13 letters)
  National Council of American Soviet Friendship, Inc., Building Industry Committee, 1946 (6 letters)
  National Council of Architectural Registration Boards, 1946-1959 (5 letters): request recommendations for Jean Bodman Fletcher, I. M. Pei, and Richard G. Stein
  National Council of Churches, 1955 (1 letter)
  National Council on Schoolhouse Construction, 1951 (1 letter)
  National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1965-1968 (47 letters): 1967 letter from Breuer includes typescripts concerning Josef Albers and Constantino Nivola; 1968 encloses a letter from Philip Johnson; see American Academy of Arts and Letters National Society of Interior Designers, Inc., 1958 (1 letter) National Terrazzo & Mosaic Association, 1955 (1 letter from Murray S. Emslie)
  National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1975 (2 letters): from Breuer's office
  Nedberg, Björn, 1951 (1 letter)
  Nederlandsch-Amerikaansche Fundatie, 1957-1958 (2 letters)
  Neighbour, Keith, 1955 (1 letter)
  Neiman Marcus, Dallas, Texas, 1961 (1 letter)
  Nelson, George (architect), undated and 1958 (2 letters)
  Nemeny, George (architect), 1945 (2 letters): from Breuer
  Nervi, Mario (son of Pier Luigi Nervi), 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Nervi, Pier Luigi, undated and 1960-1978 (5 letters): see Project File for UNESCO
  Neski, Joe and Barbara, 1957 (1 letter)
  Neski, Julian (architect), 1967-1970 (2 letters)
  Neufert, Ernst, 1946 (1 letter)
  Neumann, J. B., 1950 (1 card): sent jointly with Elsa Schmid
  Neumann, Lena, 1951 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Neumann, Vera (Scarves by Vera), 1970 (1 letter)
  Nevendorff, Peter (construction supervisor for Ludwig Mies van der Rohe's Museum of the 20th Century), 1967 (1 office message)
  Newark Museum, 1954-1955 (5 letters)
  New Canaan Advertiser, 1974 (1 letter)
  New Canaan Committee for Shakespearean Festival, undated (1 invitation): from Francis A. Sunderland to meet Sir Cedric and Lady Hardwicke
  New Canaan Community Nursery School, Inc., 1955 (1 letter)
  New Canaan Country School, 1957 (1 letter): from Breuer
  New Haven Festival of Arts, Inc., 1959 (4 letters)
  New Hungarian Quarterly, 1967 (1 letter)
  Newman, Robert B. (Bolt Beranek and Newman), 1951 (1 letter)
  Newport, Charles W. (R. S. Noonan, Inc.), 1945 (2 letters)
  Newsome, Carroll V. (Prentice-Hall, Inc.), 1962 (1 letter)
  Newsweek, 1955 (1 letter)
  New York Association of Consulting Engineers, Inc., 1970 (1 letter)
  New York Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1964 (1 letter)
  New Yorker, 1967-1975 (3 letters)
  New York Institute of Technology AIA Chapter, 1976 (1 letter)
  New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Company, 1951-1963 (6 letters)
  New York Public Library, 1966 (1 letter)
  New York State Council on Architecture, 1975 (1 letter)
  New York World's Fair 1964-1965, 1964 (1 invitation): for cocktails at Pavilion of Spain
  Nicholson, Christopher (architect), 1946 (2 letters)
  Nicholson's Sports Apparel, 1945 (1 letter)
  Nivola, Constantine, 1966 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Noever, Peter (Svoboda and Company), 1958-1968 (4 letters)
  Noirot, Genevieve, 1975 (1 letter): from Breuer's office
  Nolen, James A., 1970 (1 letter)
  Nolen-Swinburne and Associates, 1970 (1 letter): from Herbert Beckhard concerning Department of Housing and Urban Development
  Nordmann, Christian, 1934 (1 letter)
  North Dakota Agriculture College, AIA, 1959 (1 letter)
  North Dakota State College, 1960 (2 letters)
  Northey, Ned H., 1956 (1 letter)
  Norton, Clifford, undated (1 letter)
  Norton, Noël E. ("Peter"; Lady Clifford Norton), undated and 1933-1965 (36 letters)
  Norweb, Emery May (Mrs. R. Henry Norweb), 1970 (1 letter)
  Noyes, Eliot Fette (architect), undated and 1946-1974 (13 letters)
  N.V. Ingenieurs - Bureau Voor Bouwnijverheid, 1960 (2 letters)
  Ochs, Fritz, 1950 (1 letter)
  O'Connor, Vincent A. G., 1963 (5 letters)
  Oehler, Erma L. (Fuller & Smith & Ross, Inc., Advertising), 1947 (3 letters)
  Oestreicher, W. L., 1947 (1 letter)
  Ohye, Hiroshi, 1954 (1 letter): of introduction from Hyoe Ouchi
  Oklahoma Agricultural and Mechanical College, 1950 (1 letter)
  Oklahoma, University of, School of Architecture, 1966 (2 letters)
  Okudaira, Kozo, 1954-1955 (6 letters)
  Olgyay, Aladár (Hungarian architect; twin brother Viktor Olgyay) and Elizabeth, undated and 1939-1960 (12 letters)
  Olivetti, Adriano, 1956 (1 letter)
  Olivetti, Dino, 1963 (1 letter)
  Olivetti, Roberto, 1970 (1 letter)
  Olsen, Don and Helen, 1947 (1 letter)
  Olsen, Ralph, 1968 (1 letter): from Breuer
  Omega Marble, 1965 (1 letter)
  O'Neill, John C. R., and Marvin H. Segner (consulting engineers), undated (1 letter)
  On Site, 1975 (2 letters): from Breuer's office
  Oppenheim, Dennis, 1968 (1 letter)
  Ordre des Architectes, Paris, 1964 (1 letter from Robert F. Gatje)
  Originators, The, 1977 (1 letter)
  Ortega, Alvaro (Colombian architect, student of Breuer), 1960-1972 (3 letters): 1972 letter from Leonard Currie concerns a recommendation for Ortega